export const questions = [
  {
    id: 1,
    question:
      "Rama’s age is double the age of Shiva and Shiva’s age is 5 years more than Sita. Sum of ages is 55. What is the age of Shiva?",
    options: ["10", "15", "20", "5"],
    answer: "15",
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question: "4 + 8*4 - 18 / 3^2 = X. Find X.",
    options: ["34", "100", "35", "0"],
    answer: "34",
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question:
      "4 people make 4 candles in 4 hours. How many candles can 16 people make in 2 hours?",
    options: ["2", "8", "16", "4"],
    answer: "8",
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question:
      "One tap fills a tank in 4 hours and another in 6 hours. Another tap empties the tank in 12 hours. If all taps are open, how long will it take to fill the tank?",
    options: ["3", "4", "6", "12"],
    answer: "4",
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question:
      "Keep a number in mind, double it subtract 2, divide by 3, add 5. The answer is 11. What’s the number?",
    options: ["8", "10", "12", "Information is insufficient"],
    answer: "12",
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    question:
      "Height:length:breadth ratio is 1:2:3. After changes, volume becomes 144 m³. What is the original length?",
    options: ["3", "4", "5", "6"],
    answer: "4",
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    question:
      "I travel from Pune to Goa in 6 hours and return in 12 hours. Total distance 360 km. What is my average speed?",
    options: ["45", "40", "60", "30"],
    answer: "40",
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question:
      "I bought 25 balls at ₹10 each, sold with 20% profit, but refunded 5 damaged balls. What is my profit?",
    options: ["10", "0", "20", "-10"],
    answer: "0",
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    question:
      "I have two balls. Ball A has double radius of Ball B. If radius of both is doubled, how many B balls needed to make one A ball?",
    options: ["2", "4", "8", "12"],
    answer: "8",
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    question:
      "How many identical cubes of 1 dm can be made from a perfect cube of 100 cm length?",
    options: ["1", "10", "100", "1000"],
    answer: "1000",
  },
  {
    id: 11,
    question: "Which form cannot be used for future?",
    options: [
      "Present continuous",
      "Future continuous",
      "Going to",
      "Present Perfect",
    ],
    answer: "Present Perfect",
  },
  {
    id: 12,
    question: "In what context can the word 'fast' NOT be used?",
    options: ["Noun", "Adjective", "Adverb", "Conjunction"],
    answer: "Conjunction",
  },
  {
    id: 13,
    question: "'Animosity' is the antonym of:",
    options: ["Hostility", "Grudges", "Relatives", "Friendship"],
    answer: "Friendship",
  },
  {
    id: 14,
    question: "‘Ram is taller than any other boy.’ Change the degree.",
    options: [
      "Ram is the tallest boy.",
      "Many boys are taller than Ram.",
      "Very few boys are as tall as Ram.",
      "Ram is not as tall as most other boys.",
    ],
    answer: "Ram is the tallest boy.",
  },
  {
    id: 15,
    question:
      "‘When he came in the room, I had just had my dinner.’ This sentence is:",
    options: [
      "grammatically incorrect",
      "combination of past and present perfect",
      "combination of simple past and past perfect",
      "had can’t be used twice",
    ],
    answer: "combination of simple past and past perfect",
  },
  {
    id: 16,
    question: "Would you please pass the sugar?",
    options: [
      "correct sentence",
      "'Please' should not be used.",
      "'The' should not be used.",
      "A question mark should not be used.",
    ],
    answer: "correct sentence",
  },
  {
    id: 17,
    question: "Magnanimous means?",
    options: [
      "very proud",
      "philanthropist",
      "very attractive",
      "bigger than expected",
    ],
    answer: "philanthropist",
  },
  {
    id: 18,
    question: "A misogynist is a person:",
    options: [
      "Who hates misbehaving",
      "Genetically inferior",
      "Who hates women",
      "Doesn’t have manners",
    ],
    answer: "Who hates women",
  },
  {
    id: 19,
    question: "I am visiting him on next Monday.",
    options: [
      "He should be there instead of him.",
      "‘On’ should not be there.",
      "am visiting is incorrect.",
      "correct sentence",
    ],
    answer: "‘On’ should not be there.",
  },
  {
    id: 20,
    question: "‘I have been tortured for a long time’ literally means:",
    options: [
      "They have tortured me for a long time.",
      "They were torturing me for a long time.",
      "incorrect sentence",
      "They have been torturing me since last Monday.",
    ],
    answer: "They have tortured me for a long time.",
  },
  {
    id: 21,
    question: "What is the currency of Japan?",
    options: ["Token", "Yen", "Yuan", "Japanese dollar"],
    answer: "Yen",
  },
  {
    id: 22,
    question: "What’s Bheeshma’s father’s name?",
    options: ["Dhritarashtra", "Vikarn", "Devvrat", "Shantanu"],
    answer: "Shantanu",
  },
  {
    id: 23,
    question: "How many national film awards has Shabana Azmi won?",
    options: ["2", "3", "4", "5"],
    answer: "5",
  },
  {
    id: 24,
    question:
      "Who was Hambirrao Mohite’s daughter that became queen of the Marathas?",
    options: ["Yesubai", "Soyarabai", "Tarabai", "Jijamata"],
    answer: "Tarabai",
  },
  {
    id: 25,
    question: "Who invented the C programming language?",
    options: [
      "Marina Joseph",
      "Bill Gates",
      "Dennis Ritchie",
      "Bjarne Stroustrup",
    ],
    answer: "Dennis Ritchie",
  },
  {
    id: 26,
    question: "Who was the first Home Minister of India?",
    options: [
      "Indira Gandhi",
      "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel",
      "Dr. Rajendra Prasad",
      "Dr. Babasaheb Ambedkar",
    ],
    answer: "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel",
  },
  {
    id: 27,
    question: "How many test centuries did Sunil Gavaskar score?",
    options: ["30", "32", "34", "36"],
    answer: "34",
  },
  {
    id: 28,
    question: "‘Vande Mataram’ was written by?",
    options: [
      "Ravindra Nath Tagore",
      "Kavi Iqbal",
      "Bankim Chandra Chatterjee",
      "Sarojini Naidu",
    ],
    answer: "Bankim Chandra Chatterjee",
  },
  {
    id: 29,
    question: "Who is NOT a winner of the Ramon Magsaysay Award?",
    options: [
      "Nilu Fule",
      "Pandurang Shastri Aathavale",
      "Baba Amte",
      "Prakash Amte",
    ],
    answer: "Nilu Fule",
  },
  {
    id: 30,
    question: "VIBGYOR does NOT include:",
    options: ["Blue", "Red", "Brown", "Yellow"],
    answer: "Brown",
  },
  {
    id: 31,
    question: "Which one is a complete protein source?",
    options: ["Legume", "Eggs", "Mushroom", "Cashew"],
    answer: "Eggs",
  },
  {
    id: 32,
    question: "How many calories does 1 gm of alcohol have?",
    options: ["4", "9", "7", "5"],
    answer: "7",
  },
  {
    id: 33,
    question: "Omega-3 is actually what?",
    options: [
      "monounsaturated fatty acid",
      "polysaccharide",
      "polyunsaturated fatty acid",
      "vitamin",
    ],
    answer: "polyunsaturated fatty acid",
  },
  {
    id: 34,
    question: "Which is NOT a cholesterol source?",
    options: ["Fish", "Eggs", "Soyabean", "Milk"],
    answer: "Soyabean",
  },
  {
    id: 35,
    question: "Which of the following is NOT a vitamin?",
    options: ["D3", "B12", "C6", "K3"],
    answer: "C6",
  },
  {
    id: 36,
    question: "What does URL stand for?",
    options: [
      "Unique Records List",
      "Uniform Resource Locator",
      "Undefined Restricted Learner",
      "Universal Robot Location",
    ],
    answer: "Uniform Resource Locator",
  },
  {
    id: 37,
    question: "When was the first Internet network started?",
    options: ["1969", "1983", "1987", "1996"],
    answer: "1969",
  },
  {
    id: 38,
    question: "Which of the following is NOT a search engine?",
    options: ["Google", "Yahoo", "Instagram", "Baidu"],
    answer: "Instagram",
  },
  {
    id: 39,
    question: "WWW stands for?",
    options: [
      "World wide wing",
      "World Wide Web",
      "Wonders of the World Web",
      "Weekly Web Words",
    ],
    answer: "World Wide Web",
  },
  {
    id: 40,
    question: "Which of the following is a type of web browser?",
    options: ["Mozilla Firefox", "Java", "Microsoft PowerPoint", "Google"],
    answer: "Mozilla Firefox",
  },
];
